<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>conferences on Owen Campbell</title><link>https://owencampbell.me.uk/tags/conferences/</link><description>Recent content in conferences on Owen Campbell</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 09:50:01 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://owencampbell.me.uk/tags/conferences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Successful Talk Proposals</title><link>https://owencampbell.me.uk/blogs/successful_talk_proposals/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 09:50:01 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://owencampbell.me.uk/blogs/successful_talk_proposals/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been part of the PyCon UK organisers team for several years. My job in that team is to look after the programme - the call for proposals, reviewing the submissions and fitting those we accept into the schedule.
There are many guides online to writing a successful proposal. We normally have one ourselves on the conference website:
(Our 2022 Advice)[https://2022.pyconuk.org/call-for-proposals/proposal-submission-advice/]
Here&amp;rsquo;s another from Hannah Hazi whose 2022 proposal was selected as a keynote (which we&amp;rsquo;ll come back to again in a moment):</description></item><item><title>Everyone Pays to Attend PyCon UK</title><link>https://owencampbell.me.uk/blogs/pyconuk_everyone_pays/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://owencampbell.me.uk/blogs/pyconuk_everyone_pays/</guid><description>PyCon UK has a long-standing policy that everyone pays to attend - speakers, organisers, everyone. That often causes some consterntation with reactions like &amp;quot;I have to pay to speak at PyCon UK?!!&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;If I volunteer to help, I have to pay the same as someone who has done nothing?&amp;quot;
I've been party to many discussions on whether the policy should change and these are my thoughts on the subject... (TLDR: it shouldn't).</description></item><item><title>Lightning Talks and Buckets</title><link>https://owencampbell.me.uk/blogs/lightning_talks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://owencampbell.me.uk/blogs/lightning_talks/</guid><description>PyCon UK 2016 At PyCon UK 2016, I became annoyed.
I was fully part of the organising team for the first time and we had spent part of our opening morning's session introducing lightning talks: explaining how they were an ideal way for new speakers to begin their speaking career.
At the time, the system we used for lightning talks was the same as everyone else. We had a flipchart at reception and, if you wanted to give a talk, you wrote your name and a title on the flipchart, starting at the top.</description></item><item><title>My Conference Attendance Guidelines</title><link>https://owencampbell.me.uk/blogs/conference_guidelines/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://owencampbell.me.uk/blogs/conference_guidelines/</guid><description>I regularly attend technical conferences in order to learn, make new contacts and generally participate in whatever community that conference represents.
Over the years, I have found that the best way to increase my chances of making new friends and contacts is to speak at the conference - people are far more likely to approach me to discuss my talk than for any other reason.
So, for me, attendance at a conference is a big deal.</description></item></channel></rss>